Finding Aid for the Arthur Stern papers, 1938-2013 LSC.2332
UCLA Library Special Collections
- Series 1: Engineering, 1948-2011
  - Subseries 1.3: Magnavox, 1964-2004
    - Overseas trip: London, Paris, Switzerland, 1978 October-November (Box 23, Folder 8)
    - Overseas trip: San Juan, Lisbon, Geneva, Zurich, Oslo, Brussels, 1978 December (Box 23, Folder 9)
    - Overseas trip: New Jersey, Baltimore, New York, Frankfurt, Bremen, Koblenz, Switzerland, Brussels, Amsterdam, 1979 February-March (Box 23, Folder 10)
    - Overseas trip: Portugal, Spain, Monte Carlo, Switzerland, Norway, Rome, London, 1979 April-May (Box 23, Folder 11)
    - Overseas trip: Key Largo, London, Holland, Switzerland, Germany, Sweden, 1979 October (Box 24, Folder 1)
    - Overseas trip: Mahwah, Brussels, Amsterdam, West Germany, Switzerland, Italy, 1979 November (Box 24, Folder 2)
    - Overseas trip: Fort Worth, New Jersey, New York, Paris, Switzerland, Stuttgart, Backnang, Oslo, London, Holland, 1980 February (Box 24, Folder 3)
    - Overseas trip: New York, Washington DC, West Germany, Switzerland, Great Britain, 1980 April-May (Box 24, Folder 4)
    - Overseas trip: Washington DC, Stockholm, Switzerland, London, Rome, 1980 June-July (Box 24, Folder 5)
    - Overseas trip: England, Sweden, Holland, Germany, Switzerland - visits to Mullard and AGA, 1980 September-October (Box 24, Folder 6)
    - Overseas trip: Frankfurt, Kiel, Hamburg, West Germany, Switzerland, England, 1980 November (Box 24, Folder 7)
    - Overseas trip: New York, Paris, Zurich, Rome, Israel, Antwerp, 1981 April (Box 24, Folder 8)
    - Overseas trip: New York, Brussels, Paris, Switzerland, Italy, Israel, Germany, Holland, 1981 April-May (Box 25, Folder 1)
    - Overseas trip, 1981 May-June (Box 25, Folder 2)
    - Overseas trip: Princeton, Paris, Hamburg, Oslo, Zurich, Geneva, 1981 August (Box 25, Folder 3)
    - Overseas trip: Mahwah NJ, Holland, Hamburg, Bremen, London, Frankfurt, Brussels, 1981 October (Box 25, Folder 4)
    - Overseas trip: New Jersey, New York, West Germany, Switzerland, United Kingdom, France, the Netherlands (Agent's Conference), 1981 November (Box 25, Folder 5)
    - Overseas trip: Philadelphia, New York, West Germany, Amsterdam, Switzerland, Spain, 1981 December (Box 25, Folder 6)
    - Overseas trip: Philadelphia, Switzerland, Holland, Washington DC, 1982 March (Box 25, Folder 7)
    - Overseas trip: Tokyo, Hong Kong, Delhi, West Germany, Switzerland, New York, 1982 April-May (Box 25, Folders 8-10)
    - Overseas trip: Switzerland, Holland, New York, Fort Wayne, 1982 June-July (Box 25, Folder 11)
    - Overseas trip: Stockholm, Oslo, Switzerland, Brussels, Paris, London, 1982 September (Box 25, Folder 12)
    - Overseas trip: Europe, 1982 August-September (Box 26, Folder 1)
    - Overseas trip: Frankfurt, Hamburg, Copenhagen, Amsterdam, Eindhoven, Geneva, Zurich, Vevey, London, Dallas, 1982 September-October (Box 26, Folders 2-3)
    - Overseas trip: Washington DC, Fort Monmouth, Frankfurt, Holland, Sweden, Switzerland, Paris, New York, 1982 December (Box 26, Folders 4-5)
    - Overseas trip: New York, London, Geneva, Zurich, Amsterdam, 1983 April-May (Box 26, Folder 6)
    - Overseas trip: July 4-11, 1983 - Japan, 1983 July (Box 26, Folders 7-8)
    - Overseas trip: England, Norway, Stockholm, Switzerland, Hamburg, Paris, 1983 August (Box 26, Folder 9)
    - Overseas trip: GPS-related business, 1983 August (Box 26, Folder 10)
    - Overseas trip: New York, New Jersey, Germany, Switzerland, Spain, Holland, France, 1983 October (Box 26, Folder 11)
    - Overseas trip: Europe - Agent's Conference, 1983 October (Box 26, Folder 12)
    - Overseas trip: Paris, Zurich, Frankfurt, Amsterdam, New York, 1984 October-November (Box 26, Folder 13)
    - Overseas trip: Paris, Geneva, Rome, Zurich, Frankfurt, 1984 March (Box 27, Folder 1)
    - Overseas trip: Europe and Israel, 1984 May (Box 27, Folders 2-3)
    - Overseas contact information, 1985 (Box 27, Folder 4)
    - Overseas trip: London, Zurich, Paris, New York, 1985 March (Box 27, Folder 5)
    - Overseas trip: Italy, Germany, 1985 April (Box 27, Folder 6)
    - Overseas trip: New York, Rome, Florence, Zurich, Copenhagen, Frankfurt, 1985 April-May (Box 27, Folder 7)
    - Overseas trip: East Coast, Holland, Switzerland, 1985 June (Box 27, Folder 8)
    - Overseas trip: Amsterdam, 1985 June (Box 27, Folder 9)
    - Overseas trip: England, Holland, Switzerland, East Coast, 1985 October (Box 27, Folder 10)
    - Overseas trip: Fort Wayne, Philadelphia, Amsterdam, Frankfurt, Zurich, New York, 1985 November (Box 27, Folder 11)
    - Overseas trip: business paperwork, 1985 November (Box 27, Folder 12)
    - Overseas trip: Frankfurt, Zurich, Geneva, London, 1986 January (Box 27, Folder 13)
    - Overseas trip: St. Louis, Washington DC, Zurich, Geneva, Brussels, London, 1986 April (Box 27, Folder 14)
    - Overseas trip: Europe and Washington DC, 1986 June (Box 28, Folder 1)
    - Overseas trip: Hungary, Israel, Western Europe, 1986 July (Box 28, Folder 2)
    - Overseas trip: Philadelphia, Switzerland, Germany, 1986 September (Box 28, Folder 3)
    - Overseas trip: Frankfurt, Copenhagen, Stockholm, Zurich, 1986 October (Box 28, Folder 4)
    - Overseas trip: Europe - Policy Advisory Board, 1986-1987 (Box 28, Folder 5)
    - Overseas trip: Israel, 1987 (Box 28, Folder 6)
    - Overseas trip: Paris, Amsterdam, London, 1987 January (Box 28, Folder 7)
    - Overseas trip: London, Switzerland, Paris, Florida, 1987 March-April (Box 28, Folder 8)
    - Overseas trip: London, Zurich, Frankfurt, 1987 April (Box 28, Folder 9)
    - Overseas trip: Germany, Israel, Yugoslavia, Switzerland, 1987 June (Box 28, Folder 10)
    - Overseas trip: Europe - Policy Advisory Board, 1987 October (Box 28, Folder 11)
    - Overseas trip: Holland, England, Switzerland, 1987 November (Box 28, Folder 12)
    - Overseas trip: Denmark, Germany, Holland, 1988 March (Box 28, Folder 13)
    - Overseas trip: Holland, France, Belgium, Switzerland, 1988 April (Box 28, Folder 14)
    - Overseas trip: Holland, Germany, Switzerland, 1988 May (Box 28, Folder 15)
    - Overseas trip: Holland, Switzerland, England, 1988 June (Box 28, Folder 16)
    - Overseas trip: Holland and England, 1988 August (Box 28, Folder 17)
    - Overseas trip: Switzerland, Netherlands, Paris, 1988 October-November (Box 28, Folder 18)
    - Overseas trip: Zurich, Amsterdam, London, 1988 December (Box 28, Folder 19)
    - Overseas trip: cancelled trip, 1989 (Box 28, Folder 20)
    - Overseas trip: East Coast, Switzerland, Holland, Italy, 1989 March (Box 28, Folder 21)
    - Overseas trip: Switzerland, France, England, 1989 July (Box 29, Folder 1)
    - Overseas trip: England, Holland, 1989 September (Box 29, Folder 2)
    - Overseas trip: Holland, Switzerland, England, 1989 December (Box 29, Folder 3)
    - Overseas trip: England, France, Switzerland, Germany, 1989 December (Box 29, Folder 4)
    - Overseas trip: New York, Budapest, Zurich, Geneva, 1990 June (Box 29, Folder 5)
    - Calendars, 1979-1987 (Box 29, Folder 6)
    - Appointment Books, 1982-1990 (Box 29, Folders 7-8)
    - Daily Calendar, 1985 (Box 29, Folders 9-11)
    - Daily Calendar, 1986 (Box 30, Folders 1-3)
    - Daily Calendar, 1987 (Box 30, Folders 4-6)
    - Daily Calendar, 1988 (Box 31, Folder 1, Box 30, Folders 7-8)
    - Daily Calendar, 1989 (Box 31, Folders 2-4)
    - Daily Calendar, 1990 (Box 31, Folders 5-7)
    - Media: Speeches and presentations, 1983-1987 (Box 32)
      12 audio cassettes. Cassette annotations: 3 grouped together marked “Magnavox”; "Position, Location, and Navigation Symposium, 1986 Keynote" (3 copies); “Ethics in Business – 1987” (3 copies); "MRL LA Hilton"; • "A P Stern – Ethics – edited master"; “Senior Management Perceptions of Internal Auditing” 1983.
    - Professional awards, 1965-2004 (Box 72)
  - Subseries 1.4: Institute of Electrical and Electronics Engineers (IEEE), 1972-2011
    The Institute of Electrical and Electronics Engineers (IEEE) is a major international technical professional organization. This subseries includes press releases, correspondence, travel agendas, and conference materials from 1975, the year in which Arthur Stern served as President of the organization. The subseries also includes conference materials, correspondence, and awards related to Stern’s continued involvement with the organization throughout his career.
    - Certificates and recognition, 1972-1976, 1981, 2003 (Box 33, Folder 1)
    - News release: Secretary IEEE, 1972 January 12 (Box 33, Folder 2)
    - News release: Treasurer IEEE, 1973 January 4 (Box 33, Folder 3)
    - News release: Vice President - Regional Activities IEEE, 1974 (Box 33, Folder 4)
    - News release: President IEEE, 1974 November (Box 33, Folder 5)
    - Business cards and candidate biographies, 1974 (Box 33, Folder 6)
    - Office of the President article - Electrical Engineering Times, 1974-1975 (Box 33, Folder 7)
    - Venice, Italy Region 8 Committee Meeting, 1975 April-July (Box 33, Folder 8)
    - Athens, Greece, 1975 March-May (Box 33, Folder 9)
    - Correspondence and Memoranda: Popov Society - Moscow USSR, 1975 (Box 33, Folders 10-13)
    - Correspondence: Irwin Feerst, 1973-1977 (Box 34, Folders 1-3)
    - Hungarian Electrotechnical Association Budapest, Hungary, 1974-1975 (Box 34, Folder 4)
    - Vienna, Austria, 1975 June (Box 34, Folder 5)
      German materials include: Brief correspondence regarding visit while president of IEEE
    - VI Central American Convention Managua, Nicaragua, 1975 April-September (Box 34, Folder 6)
    - Mexicon 75 Mexico City, Mexico, 1975 February-October (Box 34, Folder 7)
    - International IEEE: Japan, Philippines, Australia, Hong Kong, Bangkok, India, Iran, Netherlands, etc., 1975-1976 (Box 34, Folders 8-9, Box 35, Folder 1)
    - Overseas trip: Venice, Israel, Egypt, Athens, 1975 April-June (Box 35, Folder 2)
    - Overseas trip: Finland, USSR, Hungary, Vienna, Switzerland, 1975 May-June (Box 35, Folder 3)
    - Overseas trip: Managua, Nicaragua, 1975 August (Box 35, Folder 4)
    - Overseas trip: Japan, Australia, Hong Kong, Bangkok, India, Tehran, Netherlands, etc., 1975 September-October (Box 35, Folder 5)
    - Overseas trip: the Netherlands, Italy, Denmark, 1975 December (Box 35, Folder 6)
    - IEEE Spectrum, 1975 September (Box 35, Folder 7)
    - Professional Activities of IEEE Address, 1975 August 12 (Box 35, Folder 8)
    - IEEE membership documents, 1975 (Box 35, Folder 9)
    - IEEE in Israel invitations, 1975 (Box 35, Folder 10)
    - IEEE in Israel Program, 1975 (Box 35, Folder 11)
    - Meetings with industry leaders, 1975 (Box 35, Folder 12)
    - Conference and travel programs, 1975 (Box 36, Folders 1-2, Box 35, Folder 13)
    - Correspondence: publications and articles, 1975-1976 (Box 36, Folders 3-4)
    - IEEE correspondence and newsletters, 1975-2010 (Box 36, Folders 5-7, Box 37, Folders 1-2)
    - Retrospective on the International Solid State Circuits Conference, 1992 (Box 37, Folder 3)
    - International Solid State Circuits Conference Annual Conference, 1993 (Box 37, Folder 4)
    - IEEE History Center, 1993-2009 (Box 37, Folders 5-6, Box 38, Folders 1-2)
    - IEEE History Center: John J Guerrera, 1995-2007 (Box 38, Folder 3)
    - IEEE retrospective - History Center, 1961-2007 (Box 38, Folder 4)
    - Haraden Pratt Award, 1999-2001 (Box 38, Folder 5)
    - IEEE Awards Events, 1994-2006 (Box 38, Folder 6)
    - IEEE Recognition Council, 2010-2011 (Box 38, Folder 7)
    - Media: IEEE Presentations, 1975-1990 (Box 32)
      7 1/8 inch audiocassettes. Titles/markings on cassettes: “Professional Activities of IEEE” August 12, 1975 (3 copies), "Nov. 5, 1986 IEEE Luncheon", "A P Stern May 6, 2002", 2 unmarked
    - Awards, 1975 (Box 72)
- Series 2: Publications, 1949-2004
  The Publications series (1949-2004) contains technical papers, conference proceedings, and books to which Arthur Stern contributed. It also includes his master’s thesis from Syracuse University. Additionally, the series includes newspaper articles that mention or are related to Stern, mostly in a professional context.
  The contents are arranged chronologically and by format.
  - Early publications: Switzerland, 1951 (Box 40, Folder 1)
    Bulletins of the Swiss Association for Electrical Engineers with articles by Stern on the theory of series reactors for gas discharge lamps and white fluorescent tubes, article for cold cathode fluorescent tubes about series reactors for fluorescent tubes, article in Journal for Applied Mathematics and Physics on the theory of the of alternating current circuits for discharge lamps.
  - Early publications: Switzerland and GE, 1949-1959 (Box 40, Folders 2-4)
  - Abstract: "Economic Aspects of the Impact of Microelectronics on the Electronics Industry", 1950s (Box 40, Folder 5)
  - Transistor AM Broadcast Receivers - GE Technical Information Series, 1952-1954 (Box 40, Folder 6)
  - Electronics Magazine, 1954 (Box 40, Folder 7)
  - Scientific publications GE, 1954-1961 (Box 40, Folder 8, Box 41, Folder 1)
  - Syracuse thesis: "Transistor AM Broadcast Receivers", 1956 (Box 41, Folders 2-3)
  - Scientific publications and conference records, 1960-1961 (Box 41, Folder 4)
  - Technical journals, 1951-1962 (Box 41, Folder 5, Box 42, Folders 1-2)
  - Proceedings of the Institute of Radio Engineers, 1954-1957 (Box 42, Folders 3-5)
  - Institute of Radio Engineers Convention Records, 1956 (Box 43, Folder 1)
  - Proceedings of the Institute of Electrical and Electronics Engineers, 1964 (Box 43, Folders 2-3)
  - Military Electronics, 1980 December (Box 43, Folder 4)
  - CIO Magazine, 1992 March 8-11 (Box 43, Folder 5)
  - International Solid-State Circuits Conference Digest of Technical Papers, 1993, 2003 (Box 43, Folders 6-7, Box 44, Folder 1)
  - Eta Kappa Nu "A Century of Honoring Excellence in Electrical and Computer Engineering", 2004 (Box 44, Folder 2)
  - Newspaper clippings, 1957-1985 (Box 44, Folders 3-6)
  - Bound volumes, 1953-2004 (Box 45)
    Contains 12 volumes. List of titles:
    Engineers as Executives: An International Perspective, William Aspray
    Proceedings of the Symposium on Modern Network Synthesis, Polytechnic Institute of Brooklyn, April 13, 14, 15, 1955
    National Policy and Priorities for Science and Technology Act, 1975
    Profiles in Engineering Leadership: Eta Kappa Nu’s First Century Eminent Members, Greg Swedberg
    Handbook of Automation Computation and Control, Volume 3: Systems and Components (2 copies)
    Internationale Investitionen in Entwicklungaslandern, Dr. Tibor Rosenbaum
    Transistor Circuit Engineering, ed. Richard F. Shea
    Technique des circuits a transistors, ed. R.F. Shea (French translation of Transistor Circuit Engineering)
    Principles of Transistor Circuits, ed. Richard F. Shea (includes inscription)
    Proceedings of the National Electronics Conference Volume XVI 1960
    A Century of Honors 1884-1984, IEEE
- Series 3: Personal materials, 1940-2012
  The personal materials in this series include Arthur Stern's personal correspondence with family and friends from the 1940s in postwar Switzerland up until his death in Los Angeles in 2012. Some of the correspondence, particularly with Stern’s relatives, is in German, Hungarian, and French. The series also includes black and white photographs and negatives, ephemera from post-war Switzerland, personal travel itineraries, and personal records such as address lists, bibliographies, notes, genealogy research and documentation, and letters to editors.
  Contents are arranged by subject.
  COLLECTION CONTAINS DIGITAL MATERIALS: Special equipment or further processing may be required for viewing. All requests to access special collections material must be made in advance using the request button located on this page.
  - Arthur Stern school records, 1940-1943 (Box 46, Folder 1)
  - Postwar Switzerland: photos, 1940s (Box 46, Folder 2)
  - Official documents at liberation, 1945-1952 (Box 46, Folder 3)
    German materials include: official documents pertaining to liberation and proving Stern’s subsequent stay in Switzerland.
    French materials include: official documents related to refugee status, liberation, and right to reside in Switzerland.
  - Postwar Switzerland: Bewusstsein und Sein - Swiss socialist student organization publication (Box 46, Folder 4)
    Two pamphlets containing articles from the Swiss Association of Socialist Students on the subjects of science and socialism, the applicability of Karl Marx, sociology, comparing capitalistic and socialistic economic planning models, and reports on local concerns.
  - Correspondence: Postwar Switzerland (Box 46, Folder 5)
    German materials include: program from Arthur and Edith’s wedding, bank receipts, psychological evaluation of both Robert and Arthur Stern sent to Leon Stern, correspondence regarding the unpaid bill stating their experience that Jewish clients don’t want to pay their bills, correspondence regarding Leon Stern’s order for a psychological evaluation of his sons, the official handwriting analysis of both Arthur and Robert Stern.
  - Correspondence: job applications, 1945, 1950-1953 (Box 46, Folder 6)
    German materials include: Letters from potential employers and invitations to visit certain laboratories, as well as correspondence with a professor in Switzerland.
    French materials include: Correspondence from University of Geneva law department regarding requirements for sitting exams.
  - Correspondence: employment, 1951-1961 (Box 46, Folder 7)
  - Arthur and Edith immigration and naturalization paperwork, 1946-1956 (Box 46, Folder 8)
  - Syracuse correspondence, 1956 (Box 46, Folder 9)
  - Syracuse Jewish Welfare Federation, 1958 (Box 46, Folder 10)
  - Letter to parents, 1960 June 28 (Box 46, Folder 11)
  - Correspondence: Arthur and Edith ("Our Family Letters"), 1965 (Box 46, Folder 12)
    German materials include: Letters from Edith to Arthur regarding the children (particularly their behavior and time at Aschers), her visit to Switzerland, health updates, travel plans, Arthur’s parents.
  - 515 Bradford Parkway: real estate and legal correspondence, 1959-1961 (Box 46, Folder 13)
  - 7505 Park Heights Avenue: real estate and legal correspondence, 1959-1965 (Box 46, Folder 14)
  - McGraw Hill reviews, 1959-1964 (Box 46, Folder 15)
  - Transistor Circuit Engineering and other literary activities, 1955-1963 (Box 46, Folder 16)
  - Jewish community in Switzerland, 1955-1963 (Box 46, Folder 17)
    Materials include: drafts of statute, list of board members and members of the Orthodox congregation in Geneva, notes about how the congregation should be organized and relate to others in Geneva, minutes from the meeting at which the congregation was founded and led by Leon Stern.
  - Correspondence: to parents (Leon and Bertha Stern), 1951-1981 (Box 48, Folders 1-2, Box 47, Folders 1-6)
    German language content includes:
    Folders 1-3 of 8: Correspondence primarily from Edith to Arthur’s parents (Arthur’s are mostly in Hungarian) regarding health updates, the children and their behavior and development, Robert Stern’s visits, thanking for various gifts, the search for a new house, family visits and trips, real estate/work updates, getting used to life in the US, and an official statement on Arthur’s experience while leaving Bergen-Belsen, APS correspondence regarding restitution.
    Folders 4-6 of 8: Correspondence primarily from Edith to Arthur’s parents (Arthur’s are in Hungarian) regarding their children (particularly their education and behavior), travel plans, plans for Jewish holidays, health updates, how busy Arthur is, thank-you's for gifts received, move to Los Angeles, visits from Robert and Edith’s mother, and the whiskey business. Letters from Jetty with good wishes for birthday and for the Jewish New Year, and regarding visits with Arthur and family.
    Folders 7-8 of 8: Correspondence primarily from Edith regarding health updates, travel, their children (particularly their education and development), Edith’s real estate work, business concerns, Arthur’s preoccupation with work, good wishes for Jewish holidays, birthdays, and anniversaries, and Jewish social engagements.
  - Correspondence: from parents (Leon and Bertha Stern), 1952-1976 (Box 48, Folders 3-8)
    German materials include:
    Folders 3-5: Letters from Parents 1952-63 Correspondence from Arthur’s parents, particularly regarding travel, business and financial concerns, investing in whiskey, family politics (especially regarding Robert Stern), family milestones, deliveries, holocaust reparations, current events (particularly in Hungary, though includes brief mentions of the Kasztner trial, the Eichmann trial, and the Kennedy assassination), and Stern’s children – particularly regarding their birthdays and Jewish education.
    Folders 6-8: Letters from Parents 1964-1976 Correspondence regarding travel, move to Los Angeles and real estate concerns, business concerns (primarily regarding Whiskey), financial and economic concerns (particularly regarding investments in the stock market and taxes), discussions regarding Stern’s children (particularly Jewish education, behavior, Danny and Claude’s bar mitzvah), family concerns and milestones, health updates, discussion of Jewish life and the congregation in Geneva, concerns regarding the actions of Robert Stern, move to Magnavox, holocaust reparations (very briefly), current events (particularly in Israel), congratulations to Stern on promotions within the IEEE, Edith Stern’s real estate business. Also includes a few letters from Doris Pugatsch with general life updates.
  - Correspondence: postwar, 1947-1948 (Box 49, Folder 1)
    German materials include: correspondence from Swiss Federal Institute of Technology (ETH) in Zurich regarding an application for a position, from a former girlfriend, from a lawyer regarding unpaid fees, telegrams from Vienna regarding passport, from the socialist student association regarding a series of articles Stern should write on the situation in Hungary, from Swiss officials regarding residence permit/release from internment.
  - Correspondence: to parents, 1962, 1965, 1970-71 (Box 49, Folder 2)
    German materials include: correspondence from Edith to Arthur’s parents regarding Jewish holidays, the children’s behavior, correspondence from Edith’s mother (Hulda) to Leon and Bertha Stern regarding health of Arthur and Edith, behavior of their children while parents on vacation.
  - Correspondence: Robert Stern, 1955-1973 (Box 49, Folder 3)
  - Correspondence: family and friends, 1951-1971 (Box 49, Folders 4-6)